2975 Heritage Trail Jacksonville, FI 32275

T: 407.864.0404

Email:

brian.nelson2975@gmail.com

Brian Nelson

Profile

Culinary professional with 16 years of overall kitchen experience and 10 years of restaurant management in high volume, fine dining environments. Prior work as lead baker, sous chef and executive chef positions in scratch kitchens. Expert in managing kitchen staff, developing a better world to work for hourly staff, along with managing and executing the perfect preparation of food at a reduced cost without compromising food quality and taste. Energetic, Creative, and Passionate to be the absolute best.

Experience

Executive Chef, bb's San Marco; Jacksonville, FL – 09/2021 – Present

- Responsible for all aspects of food production and menu ideation and development.

 Responsible for all new menu items and seasonal menu items along with holiday pre-fix menus.
- Successfully lowered food cost from 39% to 32%

Executive Chef, Ida Claire Town Center; Jacksonville, FL – 06/2019 – 09/2021

- Responsible for all aspects of food production and inventory management along with seasonal menu ideation and monthly "Pairing Dinners"
- Opened two 'Ida Claire's' including one locally in town center along with San Antonio, Tx.
- Successfully beat all labor and food cost projections by keeping labor below 15% and food cost below 30% consistently.
- Created a very desirable kitchen environment to work in, constantly keeping staff challenged
 and involved in the many things we are working on and improving.

 My staff was very happy and very well paid thus always crafted
 perfect food to help build brand recognition in a difficult market.

Executive Chef, Hoptinger @ 5 Points; Jacksonville, FL – 01/2017 – 06/2019

- Responsible for all aspects of food production and assisted kitchen staff during regular dining service for two separate dining floors, offsite catering, private rooftop catering events.
- Managed high volume kitchen with annual food and beverage sales at \$2.5m, keeping food
 costs at and below 30% and labor percentage below 17%,
 consistently.
- Responsible for menu improvements and specials according to current trends, using seasonal and local flavors. Created catering menu, vegan and vegetarian menu, along with seasonal menu updates.

- Catered more than 50 events annually from small private parties to 300+ person banquets.
 Catered food and beverage festivals with up to 10,000 people per day.
- Implemented and created store recipe book including procedures and yields. Responsible for creating and implementing all updates and new recipes, procedures.
- Assisted in front of house operations by opening entire restaurant, including all front of house responsibilities, 2 days a week.
- Had exceptional health code scores, with no major violations. Constantly coaching staff on health code awareness and knowledge. Always improving kitchen layout and procedures to improve health code habits.

Sous Chef, PF Changs; Jacksonville, FL – 11/2011 - 01/2017

- Managed kitchen staff by recruiting, hiring, orienting, training kitchen staff.
- Effectively scheduled, supervised, evaluated and enforcing disciplinary measures when necessary.
- Maintained a skilled, top caliber kitchen staff with proper coaching, counseling and leading employees, encouraging a disciplined work environment.
- Maintained highest standard in food quality and standards in total scratch kitchen, constantly challenging myself and staff in quality and specifications.
- Actively involved in food cost control and labor goals by effectively ordering all food and chemicals along with writing schedules and setting goals for management staff.
- Actively involved in kitchen repair and maintenance, along with kitchen cleanliness and all equipment upkeep and repair.
- Regularly interacted with guests to obtain feedback on food quality and service standards.
 Leading to positive personal relations with repeat guests.
- · Achieved and exceeded performance with projected budgets and team goals.
- Top ten in labor, food cost, profit and sales out of 252 stores. Nominated for restaurant of the year and nominated for kitchen of the year.

Education

Lake Brantley High School; Orlando, FI – Diploma, 2005 University of Central Florida; Orlando, FI